BRAD NISSEN

linkedin.com/in/bradnissen github.com/bigTimeBrad bradanissen@gmail.com 206-353-8064

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, HTML/CSS Familiar with: C#, Python
- > DevOps: Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform, serverless, agile development
- > Tools/Technologies: Git/version control, end-to-end testing, RESTful web services, Android development
- > Coursework/Focus Areas: Web development, mobile development, cloud computing (SaaS), algorithms and data structures, computer science fundamentals, Software Development Life Cycle, Intro to Software Engineering

Software Projects

Cloud Practicum January 2019 – March 2019

Divided into teams to design and build an admin portal (web application), which is hosted on Azure. On the backend development team, we are creating a REST-style CRUD API, using C# on the .NET platform with Azure's serverless functions. I am learning the importance about cloud security, API design, cross-communications between teams, and gaining a great understanding of serverless computing.

Mobile Practicum September 2018 – December 2018

Real-time stock market trading application to follow market trends in intervals of five minutes. As a team of four, we developed the app in Java to the customer needs, and specifications. Gained experience creating timer triggers in a serverless function to make HTTP request using Node.js. This function solved the problem by synchronizing updated stocks to the users.

Mobile Final Project

May 2018 – June 2018

Android application to give travelers an idea of what to tip for varied services (e.g. taxi rides, restaurants, haircuts). This was a group project for our mobile app course. I gained a better understanding of NoSQL databases, layouts, fragments, end-to-end testing, continuous integration, and how to collaborate with others using git and GitHub.

Brewery FinderJanuary 2018 – March 2018

Brewery Finder was a fun final project to locate any brewery in the world. Building this data driven website was a great learning experience to build a better understanding of how to connect different APIs. I used PHP as the backend and a SQL database, which enabled the user to have a favorite list of breweries they want to visit.

Ray's Cash-out June 2017

Desktop application built in Java to calculate tip outs for support staff at Ray's Café. Designed and built in my free time to automate a nightly process that reduced labor costs by an hour a day.

Education

Bachelor of Applied Science, Application Development, North Seattle College

Honors: President's List **GPA**: 3.98/4.00

Seattle, WA June 2019

Algorithms and Data Structures, University of Washington

UW Professional & Continuing Education

Bellevue, WA March 2019

Experience

Computer Science and IT Tutor, North Seattle College

September 2018 – Present

Aid 15 to 20 students per quarter, part-time, by tailoring study strategies to help teach computer programming fundamentals. I design creative and fun coding exercises to help reinforce learning and build new programming skills. Languages tutored are JavaScript, SQL, and Java.

Help Desk, North Seattle College

 $September\ 2017-June\ 2018$

Provided support to end users by phone, email, or on-site. Created and recovered Active Directory accounts for campus-wide groups, faculty, and students. Diagnosed and fixed computer-related/information technology issues relating to computer systems, software, and hardware.

Server, Ray's Boathouse and Café

April 2011 – September 2018

Applied quality customer service to maintain repeat guests. Ensured that food and beverage products were made and/or presented in a timely and professional manner. Prioritized guests' needs by communicating effectively so they always had an enjoyable experience. I trained 50+ employees for various roles in the restaurant.